<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>LLazyEmail Documentation Blog</title>
        <link>https://llazyemail.github.io/documentation/blog</link>
        <description>LLazyEmail Documentation Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Create a Curated Email Newsletter That Brings Results for Your Business]]></title>
            <link>https://llazyemail.github.io/documentation/blog/how-to-create-a-curated-email-newsletter-that-brings-results-for-your-business</link>
            <guid>how-to-create-a-curated-email-newsletter-that-brings-results-for-your-business</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Email marketing is the most effective channel available to marketers today.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Email marketing is the most effective channel available to marketers today.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/jqn1djzxaabkhlsqz9u5.png" alt="Image description" class="img_E7b_"></p><p>It can help you keep your business the center of attention, build thought leadership around your brand, and generate sales.</p><p>However, it also requires content, and creating content can be time-consuming.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/u9h890g85nkj6flfh7q0.jpg" alt="Image description" class="img_E7b_"></p><p>So how can marketers like you send out engaging newsletters without spending hours creating content?</p><p>The answer is to create a curated newsletter.</p><p>In this post, we'll show you what a curated email newsletter is and walk you through the process of setting up a curated newsletter that brings results for your business. However, before we dive into curated newsletters, let's first touch on the basics of newsletters, in general.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/oq9pd64gj1e49s44yjxb.png" alt="Image description" class="img_E7b_"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="how-can-i-start-an-email-newsletter-for-a-company">How can I start an email newsletter for a company?<a class="hash-link" href="#how-can-i-start-an-email-newsletter-for-a-company" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Before a company dives into creating curated newsletters, it needs to have a solid understanding of what an email newsletter is. </p><p>An email newsletter is an email communication that is sent to inform your subscribers about various topics, such as:</p><ul><li>Latest news</li><li>Advice</li><li>Product updates / launches</li><li>Important appointments</li></ul><p>These emails can cover general topics and user-generated topics that are sent on a predetermined schedule, such as weekly, monthly, quarterly, etc.</p><p>Starting an email newsletter isn't all that difficult, especially if you've already created a list of email users. </p><p>From there, you'll simply have to send opt-in emails to your subscribers to make sure they want to receive your marketing materials, and once that's done you can start sending them according to your predetermined schedule.</p><p>Starting an email newsletter isn't that difficult, especially if you've already built a list of email users. </p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/5uwti3h7w9yobdziau9e.jpg" alt="Image description" class="img_E7b_"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="how-do-you-make-a-good-newsletter">How do you make a good newsletter?<a class="hash-link" href="#how-do-you-make-a-good-newsletter" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>What makes a good newsletter really depends on the brand, industry, and target audience. The reason for this is that everyone wants something a little different which is why they choose specific activities to follow.</p><p>However, there are several ways to help your email marketing team create a newsletter that works well.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="1-dont-try-to-sell">1. Don't try to sell<a class="hash-link" href="#1-dont-try-to-sell" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Mentioning a product is one thing, as you will do it during product launches / updates, but it has to be about the reader, not you selling them something.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="2-be-short-and-simple">2. Be short and simple<a class="hash-link" href="#2-be-short-and-simple" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>It must be informative, also encouraging readers to click to learn more.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="3-again-you-should-aim-for-a-click-through">3. Again, you should aim for a click-through<a class="hash-link" href="#3-again-you-should-aim-for-a-click-through" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Click through rate (CTR) is the most common metric for measuring engagement within an email campaign. CTR is a metric that measures how many people click through an email in relation to how many emails were delivered. Essentially, the click rate is a percentage that tells you how many emails successfully achieved one click from a subscriber. This click tells you if your campaign was engaging enough to not only entice an open, but also an action from your audience.</p><p><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/knowledge-base/what-is-click-through-rate-how-can-ctr-be-calculated/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Source</a> </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="4-simplify-deactivationunsubscribe-link">4. Simplify deactivation(unsubscribe link).<a class="hash-link" href="#4-simplify-deactivationunsubscribe-link" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>It is vital to make deactivation easy for those who wish to stop receiving communications.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="5-make-sure-its-compelling">5. Make sure it's compelling.<a class="hash-link" href="#5-make-sure-its-compelling" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><hr><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="what-is-a-curated-newsletter">What is a curated newsletter?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-is-a-curated-newsletter" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>First of all, it is essential to understand what it means to care: to put together, sift and select for presentation.</p><p>Therefore, a curated newsletter is one that aggregates interesting and / or popular content on a specific topic. </p><p>Curated newsletters find the best of the best material and then collect it in one place.</p><p>Often, along with links to external content locations, the newsletter will also offer a brief commentary or summary on the pieces.</p><p>Here is an example from Campaign Monitor client SitePoint:</p><blockquote><p>The newsletter curates the best web design and development content from across the web and delivers it daily to subscribers in a simple and convenient format.</p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="why-create-a-curated-newsletter">Why create a curated newsletter?<a class="hash-link" href="#why-create-a-curated-newsletter" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>There are many reasons why people take a curated newsletter approach. </p><p>For many, it helps build their businesses:</p><ul><li>Stay on top with subscribers</li><li>Build thought leadership around your brand</li><li>Sharing interesting discoveries and resources</li></ul><blockquote><p>Curated newsletters are an opportunity to offer readers a wide range of material that you have personally selected for them.</p></blockquote><p>Plus, with so much content posted on the web, a curated newsletter has serious value.</p><p><strong>Choose your topic</strong>
The first step in creating your curated email newsletter is choosing your topic.</p><p>Will your curated newsletter contain email marketing tips and tricks? </p><p>Alternatively, will you curate content on web design trends?</p><p>Choosing your topic is one of the most critical parts of starting a curated email newsletter.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>